McIntosh & Seymour Board of Directors Records
McIntosh & Seymour Board of Directors Records
1929-1936
McIntosh & Seymour Corp.
0.75 linear ft.
Records from McIntosh & Seymour's Board of Directors meetings.
5902289
Biographical History
McIntosh & Seymour was an American locomotive company, established in 1886 in Auburn, New York. It was responsible for the manufacturing of steam and internal combustion engines in the early 1900s, and diesel engines beginning in 1910. In the 1930s, McIntosh & Seymour merged with the American Locomotive Company (ALCO). [Source: Article by Bill Vossler, August/September 2013]
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The McIntosh & Seymour Board of Directors Records consists of meeting reports.
Meeting reports consist of assembled packets from meetings. These packets were assembled after their respective meetings, as shown by the inclusion of an attendance sheet for the meeting recording who was present. Members of the board and committee changed often, which is reflected on the attendance sheets. Most of the packets include the following: financial reports (including orders and bills), letters of resolution, statement submissions, personalized letters to members requesting attendance, RSVPs for meetings, memos and notices, receipts and vouchers for fees, votes for board members (called certificates of inspectors), letters acknowledging position appointments, letters of resignation, letters accepting resignations, correspondence between board members, and lists of active prospects. A few of the packets include lists of engines, notations on engines, handwritten notes, complaints filed about a contract (3 Sep 1931), and a proposal to repeal the company code and adopt a new one (Dec 1929).
Arrangement of the Collection
Material is arranged chronologically.
Related Material
See also the
American Locomotive Company (ALCO) Records
and the
ALCO Collection
.
The Smithsonian Institution possesses the bulk of McIntosh & Seymour's archives. Their collection includes letter books, instruction manuals, price and data sheets, notebooks, design notes, blueprints and drawings, calculations and specifications, sketches, and photographs.
Subject and Genre Headings
Seymour, James A., 1864-1943; McIntosh & Seymour Corp.; Locomotive industry -- Management.; Locomotive industry -- New York (State); Attendance lists.; Balance sheets.; Correspondence.; Financial records.; Memorandums.; Minutes (administrative records); Reply cards.; Board of Directors.
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advance notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Acquisition Information
Original source and acquisition date unknown.
Inventory
- Meeting reports
  - Minutes, 1929 Dec 3; 2 packets included in folder; one for the regular meeting held at 11:00 am and one for a "second special meeting" held at 11:30 am (Box 1)
  - Minutes, 1930; each folder contains a packet for a separate meeting: Feb, Mar, May, Jul, Sep, Nov; 6 folders (Box 1)
  - Minutes, 1931; each folder contains a packet for a separate meeting: Feb, Mar, Apr, Jun, Sep, Oct, Dec; 7 folders (Box 1)
  - Minutes, 1932; each folder contains a packet for a separate meeting: Jan, Feb, Mar, May, Jun, Jul, Sep; 7 folders (Box 1)
  - Minutes, 1933; each folder contains a packet for a separate meeting: Jan, Mar, Apr, Oct; 4 folders (Box 1)
  - Minutes, 1934 Feb 1; 2 packets included in folder; one for a meeting of the executive committee and one for the regular board meeting, both held on the same day (Box 1)
  - Minutes, 1934; meeting held in Mar (Box 1)
  - Minutes, 1934; each folder contains a packet for a separate meeting: May, Jul, Sep, Oct; 4 folders (Box 2)
  - Minutes, 1935; each folder contains a packet for a separate meeting: Jan, Mar, May, Jun, Aug; 5 folders (Box 2)
  - Minutes, 1935 Sep 12, Sep 25; 2 packets included in folder; one for a meeting of the executive committee held on Sep 12, and one for the regular board meeting held on Sep 25 (Box 2)
  - Minutes, 1935; meeting held in Nov (Box 2)
  - Minutes, 1936; each folder contains a packet for a separate meeting: Jan, Mar, May, Jun, Aug; 5 folders (Box 2)